A Finding Aid to the Rose Slivka Papers, circa 1947-2006, in the Archives of American Art AAA.slivrose
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1958-2004; Series 5; 7.4 Linear feet Boxes 11-18, 22, OV 23
  - Craft International -- Empire State Crafts Alliance, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Craft International -- Financial Records, 1981-1989 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Craft International -- Financial Records, Taxes, 1985-1990 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Craft International -- Fundraising, 1978-1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Furniture (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Craft International -- Furniture (Jim Krenov), 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Craft International -- Furniture (Hans Stöckli), undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Craft International -- Furniture, Article Solicitation, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Craft International -- Furniture in England, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Craft International -- Gazzard, Marea, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Craft International -- Gilpin, J. E., undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Craft International -- Grant Proposal, National Endowment for the Arts, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Craft International -- Green, Al, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Craft International -- Hall, Rita, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Hauptman, Robert, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Craft International -- Howell, Douglas Morse, 1977-1982 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Craft International -- Hughto, Margie, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Craft International -- Ideas for Articles, 1978-1985; undated (Box 13, Folder 35-36)
  - Craft International -- Ideas for Craft International Annual, 1991; undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Craft International -- International Guild of Craft Journalists, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Craft International -- Interns, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Craft International -- Kuczynska, Maria, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Craft International -- Laky, Gyongy, undated (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Craft International -- Lesser, Max, undated (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Craft International -- Liberman, Elizabeth and Ben (Printing), 1959-1983 (Box 13, Folder 43-44)
  - Craft International -- Malaysia, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Craft International -- McDonnough, Michael, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Mendocino Art Center, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Craft International -- Minnesota Renaissance Fair, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Moore, Henry, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Craft International -- Museum, UNESCO, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Craft International -- National Council for Education for the Ceramic Arts, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Craft International -- New York Experimental Glass Workshop, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Craft International -- New York State Governor's Awards, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Craft International -- Omega Workshop, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Craft International -- Premiere Issue, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
  - Craft International -- Press Releases, 1981-1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Craft International -- Primitive Art Newsletter, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Craft International -- Proposal, Certificate of Incorporation, and New York State Registration, circa 1980-1990 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Craft International -- Prospectus, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Craft International -- Publicity, 1981-1989 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Craft International -- Raja Fuziah bt Raja Tun Uda, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Craft International -- Resumes, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Craft International -- Sherman, Robert, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Craft International -- Sjarief, Hale, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Craft International -- Submission Guidelines, 1981-1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Survival Crafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Craft International -- Television, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Craft International -- "The Treasure Houses of Britain" Exhibition (1985) (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Craft International -- "Trends" Illustrations, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Craft International -- Typesetting, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Craft International -- Velasquez, Hugo, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Craft International -- Vienna Issue, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Craft International -- Wayang Theater, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Craft International -- Wenton, Nyokman, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Women in Furniture, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Craft International -- World Crafts Council, 1981-1989; undated (Box 14, Folder 29-33)
  - Crafts of the Modern World, Craft Book Reprint, Horizon Press, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Culbertson, Jane, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Darling, Lowell, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - The Easthampton Star, 1991-2000 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Edmiston, Susan, "The Private Press", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - "The Eloquent Object," Philbrook Art Museum (1987-1988), 1986-1987; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS). (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Ferren, John, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Finkelstein, Louis, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Glass, 1979-1986; undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Grant Proposal for Craft Horizons Index, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Grants Received, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Fellowship Application, circa 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Guild Hall, undated; 1982-2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Jolyon Hofsted: Approaching Large Scale Porcelains", 1970s-1990s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - How to Collect Crafts: A Guide to Selecting and Buying Fine Handmade Works of Art, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Hugs (fan mail), 1995-1998 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Institute of International Education, Fulbright American Graduate Student Program, 1980-1981; undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Israel, Margaret, 1978-1990 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Japan Project, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
  - "Reuben Kadish and Philip Guston -- Murals, Mexico and California", undated; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Kaldis, Aristodimos, undated; 1978-1985; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS). (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
  - Kanemitu, Matsumi, 1978-1997 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - The Kitchen, 1978-1997 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lecture Tour, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Le Moyne Art Foundation, Inc., 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Los Angeles Symposium III, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1982-1996 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Maloof, Sam, 1990-1994 (Box 15, Folder 22-26)
  - "Terrie Hancock Mangat Art Quilts" (1990), Bernice Steinbaum Gallery, 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Minsky, Richard, 1988-1997 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Morikami, George S., 1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Museum News, 1980; undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Names and Addresses, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - New York Experimental Glass Workshop, 1979-1981 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - New York Foundation for the Arts, 1996-1998 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - New York State Council for the Arts, Publication Arts Workshop Grant Applications, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - New York University, undated; 1973-1994 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
  - Notkin, Richard T., 1973-1978 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "The Object as Poet" Exhibition (1977), undated; 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
  - The Octagon Center for the Arts, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - "Alfonso Ossorio", undated; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Philbrook Art Center Lecture, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Pilchuk Glass Center, circa 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Poetry Workshops, etc., undated; 1982-2001; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS). (Box 16, Folder 21-22)
  - Price, Kenneth, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Publication Arts Workshop, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Publishing, Small Presses, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Rapee, Joellen, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Rhode Island School of Design, 1980-1982; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Rosen, Bruce, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Rosenberg, Harold, 1975-1978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Judith Rothschild Foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Russotto, Paul and Ellen, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Includes documentation of Society for the Preservation of the Archives of the New York School.
  - The Scherman Foundation, 1977; undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Schnabel, Bruce, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Shaw, Richard, circa 1980 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Super Mud Presentation, Pennsylvania State University, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Charles E. Tuttle Company, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Museum, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Peter Voulkos Exhibition (circa 1977), 1970-1976 (Box 17, Folder 13-18)
  - Washington University, St. Louis, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Wayne, June, 1973-1981; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - "West Coast Ceramics" Symposium, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - World Crafts Council, undated; 1966-1983 (Box 17, Folder 22-27)
  - World Crafts Council, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - World Crafts Council -- General Assembly Meeting and Asian Regional Assembly, Oslo, Norway, 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
  - World Crafts Council -- Historical Information, undated; 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - World Crafts Council -- 11th International Craft Conference, Jakarta, Indonesia, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - World Crafts Federation, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Craft International, from Box 13, Folder 1, 1980-1987 (Box 22)
  - Oversized Craft Horizons, from Box 12, Folders 13, 17 (Box OV 23)
- Printed Material, 1952-2006; Series 6; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 18-20, OV 23
  This series consists of exhibition catalogs and announcements, periodicals, newsletters, press releases, programs, brochures, and other printed items that for the most part concern crafts or organizations and individuals of interest to Slivka.
  Printed material is arranged in rough chronological order. Additional printed material can be found enclosed with correspondence (Series 1), among writings, notes and related research (Series 4), and with subject files (Series 5).
  - Printed Material, undated; 1952-1970; Oversized material housed in OV 23 (Box 18, Folder 8-20)
  - Printed Material, 1971-1989; Oversized material housed in OV 23 (Box 19, Folder 1-20)
  - Printed Material, 1990-2006 (Box 20, Folder 1-10)
  - Oversized Printed Material from Box 18, Folder 16; Box 19, Folders 4-5, 1962- circa 1970s (Box OV 23)
- Photographs, circa 1947-1990s; Series 7; 1 Linear feet Boxes 20-21
  Additonal photographs are found as enclosures to correspondence (Series 1) and with subject files (Series 5).
  Most photographs are black and white; some are the work of professional photographers and others are snapshots. This series includes a color transparency, negatives, and many contact sheets. Photographs include portraits of Rose Slivka and images of friends and colleagues. Many were taken in the course of professional travel to craft conferences and events related to her work as editor of Craft Horizons; countries visited include Turkey, Mexico, Peru and Switzerland. A relatively small numper of photographs show family and personal events. There are installation views of an apparel show held at the Museum of Contemporary Art and "Planned for Craftsmen: A Visual Definition of the Elements of Design" at an unidentified venue. Also found are photographs of crafts persons and artists at work; some are in a folder of pictures taken by Slivka's son, Marc, and others are located in files titled "National Bronze Casting Conference," "Potters Working at the Wheel," and "Foundry Workers Casting Artwork." Slivka also maintained photographs of artwork, mainly sculpture, and of miscellaneous craft objects ranging from wooden chairs to ceramics, porcelain, and fabrics by Jack Leonor Larsen.
  - Rose Slivka, circa 1947-1987 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Family, Friends and Colleagues, 1969-1987; undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - By Marc Slivka, 1977-1978; undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Travel, Miscellaneous, 1960s-1980s (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Conferences and Other Professional Travel, 1970s-1980s; undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Craft Horizons - Turkey, Mexico, and Unidentified Travel, undated; 1972 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Craft Horizons - Peru Trip, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 17-19)
  - Craft Horizons - American Crafts Council Conference, Lake Geneva, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Craft Horizons - Sweden Trip, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 21, Folder 20)
  - Museum of Contemporary Crafts Apparel Show (1974) (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - "Planned for Craftsmen: A Visual Definition of the Elements of Design" Exhibition, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - National Bronze Casting Conference, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Artists at Work, undated; 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Potters at Work, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Foundry Workers Casting Artwork, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified People and Events, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Works of Art, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Crafts, Miscellaneous, 1976-1977; undated (Box 21, Folder 5-6)